

Location:	Saint-Petersburg, Russia
E-mail:	mgrigoriev@gmail.com
Phone:	+7 (931) 227-83-84 (WhatsApp, Telegram)
GitHub:	https://github.com/mgrigoriev

SUMMARY

Seasoned Ruby on Rails developer with experience in a wide range of technologies and projects (e-commerce, education, telecom, CRM, etc.). I pay great attention to writing clean and maintainable code, automated testing, effective communication, and deep understanding of a business domain.

SKILLS

- Ruby on Rails (5+ years)
- TDD/BDD: RSpec, Capybara
- PostgreSQL
- Background jobs (Sidekiq)
- Authentication, authorization (Devise, CanCanCan; OmniAuth; AWS IAM configuration)
- Payment system integration: Stripe, MandarinBank
- REST API
- Frontend: HAML, SASS, Bootstrap; JavaScript, jQuery, CoffeeScript
- Server setup and deployment: Linux, Nginx, Passenger, Capistrano; Circle Cl
- Monitoring: Airbrake, Datadog
- Debugging and performance optimization

OTHER SKILLS

Requirements analysis, UX prototyping.

EXPERIENCE

SHOW-SCORE, New York (remote)

Ruby on Rails Developer, April 2018 — March 2020

Show-Score is a community of people who enjoy theater.

I had been working on backend and full-stack implementation of new features/tools for members and admin team, refactoring, performance optimization, increasing of test coverage, email marketing related tasks. Implemented internal currency system, back office system for theater producers, geo location services; created API services.

Tech stack: Ruby on Rails 5, PostgreSQL, RSpec, Sidekiq, Mandrill API, Stripe, CoffeeScript, React.

AIRSTRIPE, Madrid (remote)

Ruby on Rails Developer, October 2017 — January 2018

Airstripe is a flight reservation startup. I built the site from scratch, including server setup, implementation of booking system, integration with Stripe, internationalization, and admin tools. Tech stack: Ruby on Rails 5, Postgres, Sidekiq, RSpec, Capybara, Bootstrap, Stripe Elements.

THINKNETICA, Moscow (remote)

Ruby on Rails Developer, February — October 2017

Built CRM system for a popular Ruby programming school, including modules for invoicing, managing courses, groups and students. Implemented payment system integration (MandarinBank). Created automated tests at all levels.

Tech stack: Ruby on Rails 5, Postgres, Sidekiq, RSpec, Capybara, Bootstrap.

GOSSTANDART EXPERT

Ruby on Rails Developer and co-founder, January 2013 — April 2018

Built CRM/ERP solution for managing business processes of the company.

Tech stack: Ruby on Rails 4/5, RSpec, Capybara, Bootstrap, jQuery.

USABILITYLAB

Project manager at UX agency, 2012 - 2013

Ran projects related to user experience research, design, usability testing, and eye-tracking.

KAVANGA!

UX designer, 2009 - 2012

Designed user interfaces for a digital advertising platform.

Gained a lot of experience in requirements gathering and communicating with stakeholders.

OPENTODO

Author of open-source project, 2008 - 2009

Created an open-source task management application. Tech stack: Python / Django.

KOLATELECOM

Lead software developer, 2006 - 2009

Built intranet system for business processes automation; control panel for ISP subscribers; e-commerce portal with the ability to buy movies and music. Implemented modern software development practices: version control, staging server, TDD. Tech stack: Python / Django, Perl, PHP; MySQL, Oracle.

ARCTIC MEDIA GROUP

Web-developer, 2005 — 2006

Created websites for clients of the digital agency. Tech stack: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript.

NETSL

Web-developer, 2003 - 2004

Built bug-tracking system, intranet modules, and websites, including e-commerce projects.

CODE EXAMPLES

Big Business — starter CRM/ERP app

GitHub: https://github.com/mgrigoriev/big_business

EDUCATION

Murmansk State Technical University (2000 - 2005): Management, specialist degree